Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
John Held papers relating to Mail Art
1973-2008
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Held, John
8.6 linear feet
The papers of rubberstamp and artistamp artist, performance artist, collector of mail art, and fine arts librarian John Held, Jr. date from 1973-2008, and measure 8.6 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, 18 printed diaries, letters received by Held from mail artists around the world, art work consisting of artistamps designed by miscellaneous mail artists, interview transcripts, writings, project and event files, and printed material.
Provenance
John Held donated his papers relating to Mail Art in 1999 and 2008.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
John Held, Jr. (born 1947) of San Francisco, California, is a rubberstamp and artistamp artist, participant in the international mail art network, activist, performance artist, collector of mail art, and a fine arts librarian.
Jonathan Held was born on April 2, 1947. In the mid-1970s he took the name of the early twentieth century illustrator, John Held, Jr., famous for his images of "flapper girls" in the 1920s. This name change was both in tribute to the older artist as well as an expression of Dada.
Earning a Bachelor's Degree in 1969, Held received a Master of Library Science Degree from Syracuse University School of Information Studies in 1972 and expanded his interests toward participating in the international mail art network and assembling one of the largest archives of mail art in the United States. He was mentored by mail artist Ray Johnson, and Jean Brown, a leading participant in Fluxus, and whose interest in the Dada and Surrealism movements promoted emerging art forms including mail art, visual poetry, and artists' books.
From 1981 to 1995, Held was a Fine Arts Librarian at the Dallas Public Library. In 1982, he began making artistamps, pseudo-postage stamps used as an art medium, and opened the Modern Realism Gallery and Archive in Dallas, Texas, with his future wife Paula Barber. The gallery sought to preserve the record of contemporary avant-garde cultural activity.
Held published Mail Art: An Annotated Bibliography, a five-hundred page listing of secondary sources on the field, in 1991 and in 1996 Held moved to San Francisco, California, where he established the Modern Realism Gallery and acted as curator of the Stamp Art Gallery, an exhibition space devoted to rubberstamp and artistamp works.
John Held, Jr. has lectured at the Victoria and Albert Museum, London, the Museum of Fine Arts, Havana, and at the National School of Art, Prague. He participated in international exhibitions and, since 1986, engaged in international performance work, appearing in Japan, Russia, Uruguay, and Yugoslavia, as well as in the United States. One of Held's more notable performance creations is the Fake Picabia Brothers, in partnership with artist Picasso Gaglione.
John Held, Jr. lives in San Francisco, California.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of rubberstamp and artistamp artist, performance artist, collector of mail art, and fine arts librarian John Held, Jr. date from 1973-2008, and measure 8.6 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, 18 printed diaries, letters received by Held from mail artists around the world, art work consisting of artistamps designed by miscellaneous mail artists, interview transcripts, writings, project and event files, and printed material.
Scattered biographical material consists primarily of miscelleous biographical writings and accounts. Eighteen printed diaries provide very brief descriptions of daily activities and more detailed descriptions of art mail events, conferences, and travel experiences.
Letters comprise the largest and most important series in the collection. Letters received by John Held, Jr. are from an extensive number of national and international mail artists, including Mark Bloch, Hans Braumüller, Jean Brown, William Gaglione (a.k.a. Picasso Gaglione), Dick Higgins, Ray Johnson, Shozo Shimamoto, Ryosuke Cohen, Michael Leigh, Guglielmo Cavellini, and Rod Summers. There are also scattered letters from Carl Andre and Clement Greenberg, typescripts of letters sent by Held, and a file of letters exchanged with Steve Durland.
There are twelve folders of artistamps, non-official or pseudo-postage stamps designed by miscellaneous participants in the international mail art network.
Transcripts are of interviews conducted by John Held, Jr. with some of the more notable artists involved with mail art movement Al Ackerman, John Cage, Ray Johnson, and Allan Kaprow. There are also interviews with John Held, Jr., Picasso Gaglione, and Milan Knizak, including an interview with Held conducted by Ruud Janssen.
Extensive writings by John Held, Jr. consist of catalog essays, miscellaneous essays, bibliographies, miscellaneous box set texts, and miscellaneous typescripts. Project and event files concern miscellaneous projects, tours, lectures, and exhibitions with which John Held, Jr. was involved.
Printed material consists primarily of printouts of Bibliozone issues, a newsletter, exhibition catalogs, and press releases concerning mail art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material 1990-1999 (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Diaries, 1990-2000 (Box 1; 20 folders)
Series 3: Letters, 1973-2008 (Box 1-10; 7.9 linear feet)
Series 4: Art Work, 1985-2007 (Box 8; 12 folders)
Series 5: Interview Transcripts, 1977-1995 (Box 8; 7 folders)
Series 6: Writings, 1984-2000 (Box 8; 51 folders)
Series 7: Project and Event Files, 1982-2000 (Box 8; 11 folders)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1989-2000 (Box 8; 11 folders)
Most of the series are arranged chronologically, except for the Letters series and the Art Work series, which are arranged alphabetically. Letters are arranged alphabetically first according to country of origin, then by artist's name.
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Librarians; Mail art; Performance artists
Types of Materials:
Diaries; Essays; Interviews; Mail art; Transcripts
Names:
Andre, Carl, 1935-; Blaster, Al; Bloch, Mark, 1956-; Braumuller, Hans, 1966-; Brown, Jean, 1911-; Cage, John, 1912-1992, interviewee; Cavellini, Guglielmo Achille, 1914-; Durland, Steve; Gaglione, Bill; Greenberg, Clement, 1909-1994, interviewee; Higgins, Dick, 1938-; Janssen, Ruud, 1959-; Johnson, Ray, 1927-, interviewee; Kaprow, Allan; Knizák, Milan; Shimamoto, Shozo, 1928-
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1990-1999, Series 1:; (Box 1; 6 folders)
  Biographical material consists of resumes, curriculum vita, and miscelleous biographical writings and accounts.
  - Resumes, 1990-1999, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Writings in Journal Art Strike, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Accounts, 1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Diaries, 1990-2000, Series 2:; (Box 1; 20 folders)
  Eighteen diaries consist of printed text describing daily activities, conferences and travel experiences.
  - "U.S.S.R. Journal," 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "One-Week Mail Art Performance Party in Los Angeles," 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Latin America Travel Diary," 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Goforth Journal," 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Diary of Modern Realism," 1992-1995, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - "Blinking Through Japan," 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Fake Fake Picabia Brothers Performance Tour Diary" (Eastern Europe), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Quebec Congress Diary," 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Excerpts from the Diary of Modern Realism - Eastern Europe," 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Cuba Travel Diary," 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Fake Picabia Brothers Europe Travel Diary," 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Art from the Rim: The New York Correspondence School of San Francisco Artistamp Travel Diary," 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "(Fake) Fake Fluxus West/San Francisco, A Travel Diary," 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Alternate Artquest: A Fake Picabia Brothers Travel Diary," 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Moving Into Nearness: The Fake Picabia Brothers in New York City," 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "San Francisco Diary," 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Ray/Bay: A New York Travel Diary," 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Millennial Diary," 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Letters, 1973-2008, Series 3:; (Box 1-10; 7.9 linear feet)
  This series contains letters received by John Held, Jr. from mail artists around the world. A notebook entitled "Key to the Collection" in Box 1, Folder 27 contains brief biographies, descriptions of artistic style, and history of Held's correspondence with each artist.
  Letters are arranged by country and alphabetically by correspondent thereafter. Letters by John Held, Jr. are at the end of the series.
  - "Key to the Collection," 2008, (Oversized material housed in Box 9) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Argentina (Box 1)
    - La Plata: Graciela Marx, 1987-1991, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
    - La Plata: Edgardo Vigo, 1983-1993, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - Austria (Stockerau): Martin Krist, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Australia (Box 1)
    - Brisbane: Neil Degney, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Yass, N.S.W.: Pat Larter, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Belgium (Box 1)
    - Wellen: Guy Bleus, 1982-1995, (13 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 36-49)
    - Eeklo: Jan DeBoever, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Brussels: Kristof S. Debris, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Gijzegem: Kristof DHaessler, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Hombeek: Luce Fierens, 1987-1994, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-58)
    - Liege: Charles Francois, 1987-1994, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 59-64)
    - Antwerp: Guy Schraenen, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Deerlijk: Jose Vandenbroucke, 1989-1994, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 66-68)
  - Brazil (Box 1)
    - São Paulo: Paulo Bruscky, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Recife: Leonard Frank Duch, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Bulgaria (Plovdiv): Guillermo Deissler, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Canada (Box 1)
    - London, Ontario: Michael Bidner, 1983-1987, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 72-74)
    - Scarborough, Ontario: Mike Duquette, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Québec: Jean Claude Gagnon, 1994, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Burnaby, British Columbia: Rosemary Gahlinger-Beaune, 1988-1991, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 77-80)
    - Québec: Istvan Kantor (a.k.a. Monty Cantsin), 1985-1988, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 81-83)
    - Calgary, Alberta: Don Mabie (a.k.a. Chuck Stake), 1985-1992, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 84-87)
    - Toronto: John Marriott, 1990-1992, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 88-90)
    - Vancouver, British Columbia: Ed Varney, 1986-1989, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 91-93)
  - Chile (Box 1)
    - Santiago: Hans Braumuller, 1992-1994, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 94-95)
    - Santiago: Carlos Montes De Oca, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - China (Xian): Michael Pollard, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Columbia (Medellin): Tulio Restrepo, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Croatia (Split): Svjetlana Mimica, 1991-1994, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 99-103)
  - Cuba (Box 1)
    - Havana: Abalardo Mena, 1993-1995, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 104-107)
    - Havana: Jacqueline Mir, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Havana: Luis Miret Pérez, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 2)
    - Prague: Miroslav Kliver, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Zabreh: Petr Sevck and Radana Parmova, 1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Denmark (Box 2)
    - Hjallerup: Mogens Otto Nielsen (a.k.a. Atmosphere Controlled), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Valby: Steen Møller Rasmussen, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Roskilde: Georgine Margareta Witta, 1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - England (Box 2)
    - Manchester: Keith Bates, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Sunderland: Robin Crozier, 1984-1994, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
    - London: Dictionary of Art, 1994, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - London: Eric Finlay, 1980-1989, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
    - London: Simon Ford, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - London: Stewart Home, 1988-1993, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
    - London: Paul Jackson (a.k.a. Art Naphro), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - London: Don Jarvis (a.k.a. Dawn Redwood), 1981-1993, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - London: Michael Leigh (a.k.a. A.1. Waste Paper Co.) and Hazel Jones, 1989-1995, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-31)
    - Ipswich: Michael Lumb, 1991-1995, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 32-35)
    - London: National Art Library, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - London: Andre Stitt, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - London: Stefan Szczelkun, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - York: Ainslie Waller (Make Your Mark Rubber Stamps), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - France (Box 2)
    - Levallois: Daniel Daligand, 1985-1995, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 40-46)
    - Paris: François Duvivier, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Paris: Hervé Fischer, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Toulon: Jean-Noël Laszlo, 1989-1993, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 49-51)
    - Andeville: Pascal Lenoir, 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Pantin: Christophe Mielle, 1990-1994, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 53-54)
    - Paris: Musée de la Poste, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Paris: Le Peintre Nato, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Paris: Pierre Restany, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Paris: Christian Rigal, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Straasbourg: Jean-François Robic, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Ivry-sur-Seine: Matthew Rose, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Nice: Ben Vautier, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - St. Pierre de Vassois: Darko Vulic, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - French Guiana (Cayenne): Claudine Polet, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Germany (Box 2)
    - Halle: Guillermo Deissler, 1989, (oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - East Berlin: Robert and Ruth Rehfield, 1984-1990, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
    - Dresden: Joachim Strange, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - East Berlin: Lutz Wohlrab, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Stuttgart: Sohm Archiv, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Edweecht: Klaus Groh, 1977-1990, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 70-72)
    - Berlin: Volker Hamann, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Berlin: Graf Haufen, 1986-1988, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 74-76)
    - Minden: Jo Klaffki (a.k.a. Joki Mailart), 1986-1994, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 77-82)
    - Minden: Peter Küstermann (a.k.a. Peter Netmail), 1987-1994, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 83-87)
    - Frankfurt: Henning Mittendorf, 1991-1994, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 88-91)
    - Kassel: Jürgen Olbrich, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Cologne: Geza Perneczky, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Cologne: Endre Tót, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Hanover: Timm Ulrichs, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Bielefeld: Achim Weigelt, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Ghana (Accra): Ayah Okwabi, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Greece (Athens): Mit Mitropoulas, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Guatemala (Sollá): Guido Bondioli, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Holland (Box 2)
    - Amsterdam: Ulises Carrión, 1979-1986, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 100-102)
    - Middelburg: Ko DeJonge, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Amsterdam: Henryk Gajewski, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Amsterdam: Michael Gibbs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Den Haag: PTT Museum, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Maastricht: Rod Summers, 1992-1994, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Leiden: Carola van der Heyden, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Rotterdam: Peter van Beveren, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Den Haag: Sonja van der Burg, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Oostberg: Jan Verschoore, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Hong Kong (Kowloon Tong): Ken Keobke, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Hungary (Box 3)
    - Budapest: György and Julia Galan'ntai (Art Pool), 1981-1993, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Budapest: Katalin Timár, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - India (Karnataka): Swami Nirmalanand and Viswa Shanti Nikethana, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Indonesia (Jakarta): Byron Black, 1990-1993, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Ireland (West Cork): Tony Lowes, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Israel (Migdal Haemek): Rivenzon Yanoz, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Italy (Box 3)
    - Viareggio: Vittore Baroni, 1986-1992, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 9-13)
    - Bologna: Anna Boschi, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Florence: Giovanni Brio, 1989-1994, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
    - Parma: Centro Documentazione Archivi Internazionali di Romano Peli and Michaela Versari, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Brescia: Guglielmo Cavellini, 1984-1988, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bertiolo: Piermario Ciani, 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - Salerno: Salvatore De Rosa, 1988, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Milan: Ruggero Maggi, 1984-1991, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 23-26)
    - Genova: Plinio Mesciulam (a.k.a. Mohammed), 1978-1982, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 27-29)
  - Japan (Box 3)
    - Osaka: Ryosuke Cohen, 1983-1999, undated, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 30-33)
    - Amagasaki: Mayumi Handa, 1988-1993, (2 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
    - Zushi: Kowa Kato, 1985-1989, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
    - Osaka: Seiko Miyazaki, 1988, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Kyoto: Shigeru Nakayama (Shigeru Tamaru), 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Nishinomiya: Shozo Shimamoto, 1983-1995, undated, 5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 40-44)
    - Marubavashi: K. Takeishi-Tateno (a.k.a. Aerial Print), 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Ehime: Teruyuki Tsubouchi, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Luxembourg (Echternach): Francis Van Maele, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Mexico (Box 3)
    - Mexico City: Cesar Espinosa, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Mexico City: Mauricio Guerrero, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Tepoztlan: David Zack, 1983-1987, (7 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 50-56)
  - Myanmar (Yangon): Dao Badao, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Poland (Katowice): Henryk Bzdok, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Katowice: Henryk Bzdok, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Elblag: Pawel Petasz, 1986-1991, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 59-62)
    - Warsaw: Piotr Rypson, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Portugal (Box 3)
    - Porto: César Figueiredo, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Lisbon: José Oliveira, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Romania (Timisoara): Iosif Király, 1986-1990, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 66-70)
  - Spain (Box 3)
    - Madrid: Ibirico, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Barcelona: Pere Sousa, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Sweden (Stockholm): Peter Meyer, 1984-1994, undated, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 73-76)
  - Switzerland (Box 3)
    - Geneva: Juan Aguis, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Trogen: Hans Ruedi Fricker, 1987-1995, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 78-82)
    - Edmatingen: Peter Kaufmann, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - St. Gallen: Kunstmuseum, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Bern: PTT Museum, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Genéva-Peney: Günther Ruch, 1986-1990, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 86-89)
  - Turkey (Ankara): Selvin Art Gallery, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (Box 3)
    - Tartu, Estonia: Ilmar Kruusamae, 1987-1993, (6 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 3, Folder 91-96)
    - Pakruojis, Lithuania: Jonas Nekrasius, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 97-98)
    - Eysk, Russia: Serge Segay and Rea Nikonova, 1988-1992, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-9)
    - St. Petersburg, Russia: Eugene Shashkin, 1991-1993, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Gorky, Russia: Andrew Stepanov, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Leningrad, Russia: Oleg and Olga Yudin, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Uruguay (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Montevideo: Jorge Caraballo, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Montevideo: Clemente Padin, 1984-1995, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-19)
    - Montevideo: Ruben Tani and Virginia Fernandez, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Wales (Dyfed): Barry Edgar Pilcher, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 4)
    - Odzaci: Nenad Bogdanovic, 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Odzaci: Aleksandar Jovanovic, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Beograd: Dobrica Kamperlic, 1989-1992, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 24-28)
    - Novisad: Bálint Szombathy, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Novisad: Andrew Tisma, 1986-1995, (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 30-35)
    - Beograd: Milena Tomanovic, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - United States of America (Box 4)
    - San Antonio, Texas: Al Ackerman (a.k.a. Will Greathouse), 1983-1992, undated, (9 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 4, Folder 37-45)
    - Tarzana, California: Darlene Altshul (a.k.a. Tarzana Savannah, Femailist), 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Madison, Wisconsin: Miekal And, 1985-1987, undated, (2 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 4, Folder 47-48)
    - New York, New York: Carl Andre, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - San Francisco, California: Art Com, 1984-1991, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
    - Brooklyn, New York: Gerard Barbot, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Buffalo, New York: Michael Basinski, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Milwaukee, Wisconsin: Patrick Beilman (Cowtown Art), 1981-1985, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 54-55)
    - Columbus, Ohio: John Bennett (Luna Bisonte Prods), 1983-1989, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 56-57)
    - Albany, New York: Bob Black, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Hurleyville, New York: Julie Hagan Bloch, 1987-1992, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 59-62)
    - New York, New York: Mark Bloch (Pan), 1981-1990, undated, (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 63-68)
    - Gurdon, Arkansas: Russell Butler (buZ blurr), 1981-1997, undated, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 69-80)
    - Gurdon, Arkansas: Russell Butler (buZ blurr), 1981-1997, undated, (14 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-14)
    - Tyringham, Massachusetts: Jean Brown, 1977-1991, (11 folders) (Box 5, Folder 15-25)
    - Birmingham, Alabama: Charlton Burch, 1986-1991, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
    - Seattle, Washington: C. T. Chew, 1987-1991, undated, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Long Island, New York: Buster Cleveland, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Brooklyn, New York: David Cole, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Berkeley, California: Geoffrey Cook, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Preston Park, Pennsylvania: M. B. Corbett (a.k.a. Tensetendoned), 1992-1994, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Youngstown, Ohio: Mark and Mel Corrato (a.k.a. FaGaGaGa), 1990-1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
    - Sacramento, California: Michael Crane, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Winston-Salem, North Carolina: Richard Craven (a.k.a. ri chard C.), 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Madison, Wisconsin: James Danky, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Oakland, California: Lowell Darling, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Omaha, Nebraska: Dazar (a.k.a. Omahaha), 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Seattle, Washington: Davidson Galleries, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Minneapolis, Minnesota: Jan DeSirey and Chris Dodge, 1988-1991, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Seattle, Washington: Dogfish (Robert Ruding), 1985-1991, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 44-45)